Role

ansible-galaxy -h 
ansible-galaxy init vivekrole 
ansible-galaxy init --force --offline vivekrole 
sudo ansible-playbook -i hosts vivek_orchestrate.yml –vvv

vivek_orchestrate.yml
--- 
- hosts: tomcat-node 
roles: 
   - {role: install-tomcat} 
   - {role: start-tomcat} 



Let us walk through all the keywords used in the above code −

block − Ansible syntax to execute a given block.

name − Relevant name of the block - this is used in logging and helps in debugging that which all blocks were successfully executed.

action − The code next to action tag is the task to be executed. The action again is a Ansible keyword used in yaml.

register − The output of the action is registered using the register keyword and Output is the variable name which holds the action output.

always − Again a Ansible keyword , it states that below will always be executed.

msg − Displays the message.

Usage of variable - {{Output}} -->
This will read the value of variable Output. Also as it is used in the msg tab, it will print the value of the output variable.

Additionally, you can use the sub properties of the variable as well. Like in the case checking {{Output.changed}} whether the output got changed and accordingly use it.